William J. Walls Papers
William J. Walls Papers
- Correspondence-subject files, ca. 1959-1960
  - "R General" (Box 3)
    Rose, Edna M.
    Ross, Roy G.
    Rowe, James
    Rudd, Daisy
    Rudd, Matthews S. (13)
    Ruffin, J.C.
    Russell, Louise
    Rutledge, Albert W.
  - "S General" (Box 3)
    Samson Imports, Inc.
    Sanson, Blanche (2)
    Sappington, E.A.
    Satterwhite, John H. (4)
    Savard Brothers, Inc.
    Sawyer, Psyche
    Schultz, Patrician
    Scott, Alice D. (2)
    Scott, Mabelle B.
    Scott, Ruth
    Sebastian, Pearlene A.
    Shaw, Benjamin G. (2)
    Sheares II, Reuben A. (4)
    Shelton, Gene
    Sherlock, Hugh B.
    Sherrill, R.W.
    Shine, Eskimo
    Shortridge, W.E.
    Shuttlesworth, F.L.
    Siemanowski
    Siler, Lee Clinton (6)
    Sink, Henry H.
    Smith, Charles and Theodora
    Smith, Leslie L. (11)
    Smith, Letitia
    Smith, Marshall M.
    Smith, Moses T.
    Smith, Percy, Jr. (2)
    Smith, Robert C.
    Smith, W.L.
    Smith, William M. (2)
    Spaudling, McLean (3)
    Speaks, R.L. (2)
    Speas, L.B. (2)
    Speight, S.A.
    St. Francis Hotel
    Stephen Wise Congress House
    Stephens, Raymond E. (2)
    Steven, James C.W.
    Stewart, James E.W. (5)
    Stewart, Richard G.
    Stith, Gertrude
    Stringfield, John A. (3)
  - Subscriptions – Books, Magazines, Papers (Box 3)
  - "T General" (Box 3)
    Talley, John Shaw
    Taub, Allan (3)
    Taylor, Anne P.
    Taylor, L. Barbara J. (3)
    Taylor, Shelly C.
    Thomas, George (2)
    Thomas, Priscilla N.
    Thomas, Rodney
    Thombs, Leo L. (3)
    Thompson, Era Bell
    Thornton, Sarah J. (3)
    Tillman, Ella M. (2)
    Tillman, Harrel G. (2)
    Tillman, Henry D.
    Tomilson, Millicent (3)
    Trent, William J. (2)
    Trent, William J. Jr.
    Tress, J.S.N.
    Trumpe, Carol
    Tyler, Marion
  - Telegrams – Incoming (Box 3)
  - Telegrams – Outgoing (Box 3)
  - "U General" (Box 3)
    Urrows, Henry H.
  - "V General" (Box 3)
    Van Doren, Mark (2)
    Vantage Press
    Vastie, Lillie M.
    Vufhuis, Tyrell
  - "W General" (Box 3)
    Wactor, Hildred H.
    Walker, R.L.
    Walker, Yvonne O.
    Wallace, Ida L. (2)
    Wallace, William P.L.
    Walters, Zoe A. (4)
    Walton, Joseph L.
    Ward, Milton Nelson (4)
    Watis, R.W.
    Watkins, Donnie
    Watkins, E.K. (2)
    Watkins, Johnsie (5)
    Watson, M.R.
    Watts, C.W.
    Watts, Leon W. II (3)
    Wegner, Nicholas H.
    Welliek, J.A. (2)
    Wells, Floretta E.
    Wells, I.J.K (4)
    Wentzel, Fred D.
    White, A.E.
    White, Reid R. (2)
    Wilcox, C.L. (2)
    Wilkins, H.T. (2)
    Williams, Addie (2)
    Williams, Dogan W. (2)
    Williams, E.M. (4)
    Williams, James R.
    Williams, M.C.
    Williams, Milton Alexander
    Williams, Muriel J.M.
    Williams, L.A.
    Williams, S.H.
    Williams, Sarah B.
    Williams, Thelma
    Williamson, Martha (2)
    Witherspoon, N.J.
    Woodhouse, enoch A. (2)
    Wright, R.R., Jr.
  - W.J. Walls – Personal – Biography, Tributes, Honors (Box 3)
  - W.J. Walls – Personal – Personal Correspondence (Box 3)
  - W.J. Walls – Personal – Speeches and Addresses (Box 3)
  - W.J. Walls – Personal – Writings and Sermons (Box 3)
  - "X,Y,Z General" (Box 3)
    Yates, Walter L.
    Young, Damon P.
- Correspondence-subject files, ca. 1961-1963
  - "A General" (Box 3)
    Aggrey, Rose Douglass
    Agurs, Edward R.
    Allen, F.M.
    Alstork, Willie G. (2)
    Anderson, Herman L.
    Anthony, Raymond
    Asante, Samuel K.
  - Appreciation – Thank You expressions (Box 3)
  - Christian Education (Box 3)
  - Church School Literature (Box 3)
  - Church Extension (Box 3)
  - Connectional Council (Box 3)
  - Discipline – Hymnals (Box 3)
  - Evangelism (Box 3)
  - Finance Department (Box 3)
  - Bishops
    - Anderson, F.S. (Box 3)
    - Brown, W.C. (Box 3)
    - Canthen, J.D. (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Board of Bishops) (Box 3)
    - Hilliard, H.J. (Box 3)
    - Jones, R.L. (Box 3)
    - Lartey, S. Dorme (Box 3)
    - Medford, H.T. (Box 3)
    - Pope, D.C. (Box 3)
    - Shaw, H.B. (Box 3)
    - Slade, W.W. (Box 3)
    - Spottswood, S.G. (Box 3)
    - Stewart, W.A. (Box 3)
    - Tucker, C.E. (Box 3)
  - Foreign Missions (Box 3)
  - General Secretary (Box 3)
  - Home Missions (Box 3)
  - Publishing House (Box 3)
  - Public Relations Department (Box 3)
  - Quarterly Review (Box 3)
  - Star of Zion (Box 3)
  - "B General" (Box 3)
    Babington-Johnson, J.A.
    Bachman, John W.
    Bagley, Nellie H.
    Banks, Thomas J.
    Baptiste, Louis J.
    Barnetts, Etta Moten and Claud A.
    Batts, Mary (2)
    Bell, A.C. (4)
    Belle, Ida
    Belton, J.A. (3)
    Bennett, Alice R.
    Bentley & Simon, Inc.
    Bess, Hunter B. (7)
    Blackledge, L.B.
    Blake, A.J.
    Blake, Eugene Carson
    Blout, Gwendolyn
    Bonner, H.D.
    Boyce, Josephine
    Bradley, Samuel
    Bridges, D. Booker
    Brooks, G.A.
    Brown, Aaron
    Bunton, Henry C.
    Burke, C.D.
    Burke, S.J.
  - "C General" (Box 3)
    Caldwell, Louico C. (2)
    Campbell, R.D.
    Canty, Marietta
    Carey, Archibald James
    Carrington, William Edward (4)
    Carrington, W.O.
    Carrington, William R. (2)
    Carson, O. Davis (3)
    Carter, Elmer A.
    Cauthen, Joseph Dixon
    Churchill, Frank E. (3)
    Clarke, L.C.
    Clay, Charles G.
    Clement, Harold A.L.
    Cochrane, William G.
    Coffey, Josephine
    Coleman, Alcestis (3)
    Coleman, C.R.
    Coles, L.F.
    Collins, Daniel
    Con Edison Company – W.E. O’Connell
    Cooper, William A. (13)
    Copeland, Dorothy M. (2)
    Corrothers, D.R.
    Councill, R.A.
    Cowan, Creola B.
    Cram, Ambrose L. Jr.
    Cross, Pauline L.
    Curtis, J.C.
    Cuthbertson, M.R. (2)
  - Circular – Incoming (Box 3)
  - Circular – Outgoing (Box 3)
  - "D General" (Box 3)
    Daniel, Ted L. (2)
    Daniels, C.H. (4)
    Daniels, Lucille
    Davis, Joseph E.
    Davis, Lola
    Deberry, P.S.
    Denman, Harry
    DesVerney, Bertha
    Dinkins, Pearl L.
    Donowa, Delancy Grecian (2)
    Douglas, Daisy E.
    Douglas, Osborne
    Douglas, William P. (2)
    DuBarry, Mr. and Mrs.
    Dunston, Alfred G., Jr. (2)
    Durham, John E. (3)
  - "E General" (Box 3)
    Edwards, Lorna (2)
    Elam, Harry J.
  - "F General" (Box 3)
    Fenderson, William
    Fitzgerald, George L.
    Flack, French Z. (2)
    Fleming, Monroe H.
    Foggie, Charles H. (2)
    Foil, Linwood
    Foster, Ethel
    Foster, Richard A.G. (3)
    Fowler, Margaret C.
    France Royal W. (2)
    Francis, Marth B. (5)
    Francis, Richard L.
    Frazer, John T.
    Frazier, Moses W.
    Fulghram, E.M.
  - Foreign Letters and Stamps (Box 3)
  - First District Youth Conferences
    - Freedom Centennial: First Epis. District (Box 4)
    - New England Conference: First Epis District (Box 4)
    - New England Conference (Box 4)
    - Western New York Conference: First Epis. District (Box 4)
    - Western North Carolina Conference: First Epis. District (Box 4)
  - "G General" (Box 4)
    Gantt, Carolyn Rebecca
    Gill, Lonia M.
    Goff, Mazie (5)
    Gomez, Joseph
    Grady, Nathaniel Thomas
    Graham, R.
    Grasty, J. L.
    Graves Family
    Gray, John
    Great Sermons Service
    Green, Sampson
    Gudger, Dean (2)
    Gulette, R.W. (2)
  - "H General" (Box 4)
    Handy, Ruth A.
    Hardge, Arthur L. (2)
    Harmon, Josephine (2)
    Harper, Addie
    Harpur College
    Harris, D.
    Harris, Roger
    Harrison, Eunice
    Harrison, Julie
    Hartman, Vladimir E.
    Harvey, Dexter
    Haynes, Olyve Jeter (2)
    Hogh, Blanco Sr.
    Hinton, Bessie L.
    Hobby, Henry G. (2)
    Hoffman, Donals W.
    Holt, Bertha (2)
    Houston, Saide M.
    Howard, Theodore D.
    Hunter, George W. (2)
    Hunter, R.T. (7)
    Hurley, Minnie D. (3)
  - "I General" (Box 4)
    Ingle, Norman Jewelers
    Irvis, H.W.
  - Invitations (Box 4)
  - Institutions
    - Camp Barber Memorial (Box 4)
    - Camp Dorothy Walls (Box 4)
    - Clinton Junior College (Box 4)
    - Harriet Tubman Home (Box 4)
    - Hood seminary (Box 4)
    - Lake Placid (Box 4)
    - Livingstone College (Box 4)
  - "J General" (Box 4)
    Jackson, Belvie H.
    Jackson, Comeron W.
    Jackson, Mr. and Mrs. E. Franklin
    Jackson, William C.
    Jarrett, Richard H.
    Jiles, William J. (2)
    Johns, Altona
    Johnson, C. Asapansa
    Jones, Frank E.
    Jones, Harriet B.
    Jones, R.C. (3)
    Jones, Raymond
    Jones, Wayne R.
  - "K General" (Box 4)
    King, Richard E.
    Knight, Frederick W.
  - "L General" (Box 4)
    Lasartemay, Ruth H. (2)
    Laws, G.W.A.
    Laws, Phillippa
    Lawson, L.A.
    Leak, Hattie M. (2)
    Leake, G.J. (2)
    Leake, M.M.
    LeMar, Aris
    Lenoir, William H. (3)
    Lewis, Louise Foster
    Ligins, Marion (2)
    Lindsay, Lizzie
    Lockhart, DeVera J.
    Lohr, Clahr
    Lomax, S.R. Mr. and Mrs.
    Long, Makepeacet
    Lowrey, Simon (3)
    Lutheran Church Supply Store
    Lyone, Grady
  - "M General" (Box 4)
    Maize, George W.
    Manufacturers Hanover Trust
    Mapp, Andrew Wesley
    Marshall, Arthur Jr. (2)
    Marshall, C.B. (3)
    Matthews, John A.
    Mays, Benjamin E. (2)
    Michael, E. Raphael (8)
    Mihos, George L.
    Miller, J. Quinter
    Miller, Jessie I.
    Miller, John H.
    Moore, Irene and I. Albert
    Moore, Yuda
    Mundy, James A.
    Murphy, Carl
  - "Mc General" (Box 4)
    McDaniel W.L.
    McDew, Meana L.
    McKay, Rose G.
    McKinney, C.G.
    McKinney, Carnes
    McKinney, Petty D. (3) McKissick, Ernest B.
    McMillian, J.Q.
    McMillian Joseph
  - "N General" (Box 4)
    Nelson, J.C. (2)
    Newton, C.O.
    Noflin, Asrean (2)
    Norment, Estelle (2)
    Nowville, H.B.
  - "O General" (Box 4)
    O’Banyoun, Bessie
  - Organizations
    - American Bible Society (Box 4)
    - Church Federation of Greater Chicago (Box 4)
    - Core (Box 4)
    - International Society of Christian Endeavor (Box 4)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - National Conference on Religion and Race (Box 4)
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ General Assembly, 1963 (Box 4)
    - Protestant Council of Churches New York (Box 4)
    - World Council of Churches (Box 4)
    - World Council of Churches Third Assembly (Box 4)
    - World Methodist Council (Box 4)
    - World Council of Christian Education and Sunday School Convention (Box 4)
  - "P General" (Box 4)
    Park, Charles L.
    Parker, Arthur J.
    Parks, Cornelia
    Penry, E.G.
    Perch, Mary B.
    Perry, Sandy
    Person, M.J.
    Philip, P.P.
    Philson, Rosa W.
    Pike, James A.
    Poling, Daniel A. II
    Porte, Rawle S.
    Powe, T.M.
  - Photographs (Box 4)
  - Programs (Box 4)
  - Public Relations: News Articles and Clippings (Box 4)
  - "Q General" (no contents) (Box 4)
  - "R General" (Box 4)
    Randolph, A. Philip (2)
    Ransom, Revery C. III
    Reape, Wilfred V.
    Rice, Willa Mae (8)
    Rickert, Carrie
    Rivers, W.J.
    Roan, H.S. (3)
    Roberts, Leonard J. Jr.
    Robinson, Bette
    Robinson, Hilyard R.
    Rockefeller, Nelson A. (2)
    Rodger, Patrick C.
    Rodney, R.C.
    Rollins, Mary A. (2)
    Romano, Joshua
    Rudd, M.S. (3)
  - "S General" (Box 4)
    AVS
    Sandum, Howard
    Schwartz, Lawrence
    Scott, N.R. (2)
    Scott, David H.
    Seamans, Harry W. (3)
    Siler, Lee Clinton (4)
    Sisler, George F.
    Sloan, James McArthur
    Smith, Anna F.
    Smith, J. Franklin (2)
    Smith, Leslie L. (3)
    Snider, W.F.
    Spauling, A. McL. (3)
    Spregne, R.E.
    Stepheno, R.E.
    Stewart, James E.W.
    Stone, Samuel M. (2)
    Sutherland, Alec
    Swartz, Betty
  - "T General" (Box 4)
    Taub, Allan
    Taylor, Anne (4)
    Taylor, Carrie H. (2)
    Taylor, Ethel (3)
    Taylor, L. Barbara Jones (3)
    Thomas, Carl Alan (3)
    Thomas, George and Farrel (2)
    Thomas, L.L.
    Thomas, P. Newby
    Thomas, S.P.
    Thornhill, Sadie
    Thurstn, P.F.
    Tillman, Harrel G. (7)
    Travalee, Elliot S.
    Treavale, Elliot S.
    Trent, William J. (4)
    Triadaway, Elizabeth
    Tucker, Amelia M. (2)
    Tucker, Dorothy and Jean
  - Telegrams – Incoming (Box 4)
  - Telegrams – Outgoing (Box 4)
  - "U General" (no contents) (Box 4)
  - "V General" (Box 4)
    Vaughn, Florence S.
    Vaughn, Shirley M.
    Van Putten, C.L. (3)
  - "W General" (Box 5)
    Wallace, Ida S.
    Walser, Horace C.
    Walters, Zoe A. (2)
    Walton, Joseph
    Wang, Thomas T.H.
    Ward
    Ward, Dr.
    Warren, C.C.
    Washington, Abraham W. (3)
    Waters, V.K. (2)
    Watkins, Johnsie
    Watson, Emma B. (2)
    Watson, J.W.
    Watts, Leon W.
    Watts, Thomas G.
    Webber, G.W.
    Wells, I.J.K. (2)
    White Reid R.
    White, William Wilton
    Whitfield, A. (3)
    Whitney, John Hay
    Whitted, A.E. (2)
    Wicke, Lloyd, C.
    Wilcox, Clinton L. (3)
    Wilkes, William R.
    Williams, Alivette and Mattee
    Williams, J.B.
    Williams, John W.
    Williams, S.H. (2)
    Williams, Sarah B. (2)
    Wilsen, Horace C.
    Winstead, Cattie
    Wisdom, David P. (3)
    Witherspoon, William Franklin (3)
    Woodhouse, Enoch O’D II (2) Woodhouse, Gertrude (3)
    Woodson, David (2)
    Wynn, Mae Sue
  - W. J. Walls, Personal – Biography (Box 5)
  - W. J. Walls, Personal – Correspondence (Box 5)
  - W. J. Walls, Personal – Speeches and Addresses, Sermons (Box 5)
  - W. J. Walls, Personal – Tributes and Honors (Box 5)
  - W. J. Walls, General Files – Writings and Addresses (Box 5)
  - W. J. Walls, Subject Files – Writings and Addresses (Box 5)
  - "X,Y,Z General" (Box 5)
    Yates, W.L.
- Correspondence-subject files, ca. 1964
  - "A General" (Box 5)
    Alstork, C.D.
    Anthony, Elizabeth
    Armstrong, David and Elaine
    Asbury, L.C.
  - American Bible Association (Box 5)
  - "B General" (Box 5)
    Baker, Corrine Statum
    Barchoff, Herbert
    Bascom, Willia
    Baskin, Ronald
    Belton, John A.
    Blackwell, George L. (2)
    Bradley, David H.
    Brooks, Ethel W.
    Brown, Frank R. (2)
    Brown, S.L. (2)
  - Board of Bishops (Box 5)
  - "C General" (Box 5)
    Campbell, Sam Vernon
    Carey, Archibald J.
    Couthen, Georgia Little
    Clayton, Robert L.
    Clement, Harold A.L. (2)
    Councill, Richard A.
    Cuthbertsen, M.R.
  - "D General" (Box 5)
    Delany, Hubert T.
    Donaldson, U.L.
    Doubleday and Company, Inc.
    Duncan, S.E. (2)
    Dunston, Alfred G.
  - "E General" (Box 5)
    Eichelberger, James W. (3)
    Eta, Y.E.O.
  - "F General" (Box 5)
    Fialkow, Jay L.
    Foggie (2)
    Foster, Richard A.G.
    Fraser, Donald M.
    Misc. Envelope from Ghana
  - First District Conferences (Box 5)
  - "G General" (Box 5)
    Gordon, Charles R.
    Graham, Edward Mansfield (3)
    Grant, L.
  - General Conference, 1964 (Box 5)
  - G.C. Correspondence Program (Box 5)
  - "H General" (Box 5)
    Harrison, Eunice B.
    Hartzler, Omar L.
    Hebster, Ben M. (2)
    Hilliard, W.A. (2)
    Hunt, Earl G.
  - "I General" (no contents) (Box 5)
  - Invitations (Box 5)
  - "J General" (Box 5)
    Jacks, William M.
    Jackson, Abbie
    Jackson, T.S.
    Jones, Al.
    Jones, Edwin L, Esq.
  - "K General" (Box 5)
    Kennedy, William T., Jr.
    Kyles, Josephine H.
  - "L General" (Box 5)
    Lartey, S. Dorme (7)
    Leake, Hattie
    Little, Andrew
    Long, Willie Jr.
  - Local and State Council of Churches: Organizations (Box 5)
  - Livingstone College: Institutions (Box 5)
  - "M General" (Box 5)
    Maize, George W. III
    Manfred, Ernest F.
    Martin, Louis
    May, Arthur E.
    Mays, Booker T.
    Medford, Hampton Thomas
    Meeks, Mary H.
    Michael, E. Raphael
    Moore, Ercelle Harmon (2)
    Morris, A.P. (5)
  - "Mc General" (Box 5)
    McCall, James Edward
    McKnight, W,J,H,
  - "N General" (Box 5)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ, USA (Box 5)
  - News Articles and Clippings: Public Relations (Box 5)
  - "O General" (no contents) (Box 5)
  - "P General" (Box 5)
    Payton, Benjamin F.
    Peterson, Earl
    Pope, Daniel Carlton
    Porter, Parree
  - Programs (Box 5)
  - Photographs (Box 5)
  - "Q General" (no contents) (Box 5)
  - "R General" (Box 5)
    Richardson, L.M.
    Robinson, M.B. (2)
    Roy, Ralph Lord
    Russell, Eleanor
    Willa Mae
  - "S General" (Box 5)
    Satterwhite, John H. (2)
    Scott, Merinetta H.
    Seabrook, J.W.
    Seagle, Andrew David
    Shaw, Benjamin Garland, Jr.
    Shaw, Herbert Bell (2)
    Sizer, Ralph M.
    Speller, Robert
    Spottswood, Stephen Gill (2)
    Sweeting, Earl
  - "T General" (Box 5)
    Taylor, Ethel
    Thomas, George B.
    Tross, J.S.N. (2)
    Tuller, Edwin H.
  - Telegrams: Incoming-Outgoing (Box 5)
  - "U General" (Box 5)
    Uphaus, Willard
  - "V General" (no contents) (Box 5)
  - "W General" (Box 5)
    Walker, Marcus
    Watts, L.W.
    Weaver, Robert C.
    Wiggins, Rex
    Wilkins, Roy
    Williams, E.M.
  - W.J. Walls, Personal Correspondence (Box 5)
  - World Council of Churches (Box 5)
  - World Methodist Councils: Organizations (Box 5)
  - "X, Y, Z General" (Box 5)
    Yelton, Nathan H.
- Correspondence-subject files, ca. 1969
  - "A-B" (Box 5)
    Allen, J. Roy L.
    Anderson, Felix S. (2)
    Bailey, J. Martin
    Barber, Alden G.
    Brown, Frank R.
    Brown, S.L. (3)
    Brown, Warren
  - AME Zion Church and Board of Bishops (Box 5)
  - "C-D" (Box 5)
    Cooke, Terence Cardinal
  - "E-F" (Box 5)
    English, Arthur
    Eyo, Okon A.
    Felton, Corroll, M.
  - "G-J" (Box 5)
    Gilliam, W.M.
    Hemphill, J.T.
    Hilliard, William Alexander
    H.I.R.E.
    Hoggard, J. Clinton
    Hyett, Mattie N.J.
    Jackson, Abbie C.
    Jones, Raymond L. (2)
  - "K-M" (Box 5)
    Khan, A.H. and family
    Kyles, Alphonso
    Lartey, S. Dorme
    Leake, George J. (2)
    Meeks, N.L.
    Morris, A.P.
  - Livingstone College (Box 5)
  - "N-R" also Photographs, News Articles (Box 5)
    Robinson, M.B. (3)
    Rogerson, I.E.
    Rustin, Bayard (3)
    Sherrill, Josephine Price
    Sisco, Vicki
  - National Council of Churches, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Programs: Public Relations (Box 5)
  - "S" (Box 5)
    Satterwhite, John H.
    Saunder, Tahitha S.
    Schuyler, Philippa Memorial Foundation
    Shipman, F. George
    Siler, Lee C.
    Smith, Gertrude K.
    Smith, William M.
    Spottswood, Stephen Gill (5)
    Stewart, William a. (2)
  - "T-Z" (Box 5)
    Taylor, Robert T.
    Temple, John F.
    Trent, Bill
    Tucker, C. Enbank
    Turner, Charles C.
    Udo, Sampson J.
    Walls, W.J. (3)
    Warlick, Dan
    Walters, Loren
    Werner, Hazen G.
    Western NC Conference
    Wilson, J. Homer
    Wright, Howard E.
    Zeff, Daniel O.
  - W.J. Walls, Personal Correspondence (Box 5)
  - World Council of Churches Fourth General Assembly: Organizations (Box 5)
  - Writings and Addresses (Box 5)
  - W.J. Walls, Personal Tributes-Honors (Box 5)
  - Subject Files: Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Subject File: Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Tribute and Honors (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 6)
  - Bishop Walls Biographical Data (Box 6)
  - Quadrennial General (Box 7)
  - Subject Files: Miscellaneous (Box 7)
- 1981 additions
  - Books - Eleventh World Methodist Conference and The Romance of a College (Box 1)
  - Camp Dorothy Walls and other miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 1)
  - Conference proceedings, AME Zion Church, local and regional conferences
    - African Methodist Episcopal Zion (AME Zion) Church, 1936; 1950,; 1966 (Box 2)
    - Allegheny Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1937-1939; 1941-1942,; 1946-1947,; 1949-1951; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Blue Ridge Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1963-1967 (Box 2)
    - Indiana Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1937-1942; 1945-1947; 2 foldres (Box 2)
    - Kentucky Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1939-1944 (Box 2)
    - New England Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1929-1932; 1934,; 1937-1938,; 1940,; 1942-1951,; 1955-1956,; 1960-1963; 6 folders (Box 2)
    - New York Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1945; 1947-1949,; 1952-1954,; 1957-1959,; 1961-1963; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Western Alabama Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1925-1929 (Box 3)
    - Western New York Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1944; 1946-1949,; 1951-1954,; 1956,; 1958-1964,; 1966; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Western North Carolina Conference of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, 1951; 1955,; 1957-1959,; 1961-1967; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence
    - Letters, 1946-1975 (Box 1)
    - Greeting cards and postcards (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 1)
  - Personal Material, will, photographs, bills, etc. (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Miscellaneous, 1928; 1918-1952,; 1954-1964,; 1967-1974,; undated (Box 1)
    - Reports by W.J. Walls (Box 1)
    - The Rise of the Negro Church (Box 1)
    - Portfolio for board members of the Zion Church (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 3)
- 1983 additions
  - Prophets of Freedom by Bishop W.J. Walls, type script (Box 1)